<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-31T20:31:41-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Georgia Danehy</title><subtitle>I am a Maker based in Los Angeles pursuing a degree
 in Computer Engineering and Computer Science from USC. 
 I get excited about Technology, Urbanism, and obscure musical instruments! </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Le-Chord</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/02/01/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Le-Chord" /><published>2023-02-01T03:51:39-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T03:51:39-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/02/01/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2023/02/01/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years I have become increasingly interested in obscure musical instruments. One of my favorites is the Omnichord, an electronic instrument released in 1981 by the Suzuki Musical Instrument Corporation. The Omnichord was originally designed to be an electronic version of the autoharp, sometimes also referred to as a chord zither. To play the instrument you press a button corresponding to a chord, and “strum” a set of touch sensors to play each note in the chord. Over the past few decades the instrument has amassed a cult following, which has led its price on ebay to shoot through the roof!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a broke college student, buying an Omnichord is placed firmly out of reach. However, I have access to something other broke college students may not have, 60% of a degree in Computer Engineering, and a club where the whole point is to make random engineering projects!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am now working on building an Omnichord like instrument with a group of people from makers.  The project is called “Le-Chord” because the foundation of the instrument is a midi-controller kit called “Le-strum”. Having only completed 60% of a degree in computer engineering I don’t have quite the skills necessary to make an the instrument entirely in hardware, so instead we are combining the midi-controller and a raspberry pi (a small single board computer) into a single instrument.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html">Over the last few years I have become increasingly interested in obscure musical instruments. One of my favorites is the Omnichord, an electronic instrument released in 1981 by the Suzuki Musical Instrument Corporation. The Omnichord was originally designed to be an electronic version of the autoharp, sometimes also referred to as a chord zither. To play the instrument you press a button corresponding to a chord, and “strum” a set of touch sensors to play each note in the chord. Over the past few decades the instrument has amassed a cult following, which has led its price on ebay to shoot through the roof!</summary></entry></feed>